William Safire Papers
William Safire Papers
- Writings
  - Books
    - Scandalmonger
      - Research notes
        - British Honour and Humanity; Or, The Wonders of American Patience, James T. Callender (Box 512)
        - Callender-Jefferson (Box 512)
        - Callender/Jellison (Box 512)
        - Charters of Freedom (Oversize 28)
        - Cobbett, William, 2 folders (Box 512)
        - Cutting letter to Stanton (Box 512)
        - The Declaration of Independence: The Story of a Parchment (Box 520)
        - The Formation of the Union (Oversize 28)
        - The Formation of the Union (Box 520)
        - Grotjan memoir (Box 512)
        - Hamilton (Box 512)
        - Hamilton/Boyd (Box 512)
        - Hamilton/Croswell, 2 folders (Box 512)
        - Hamilton interview (Box 512)
        - Hamilton papers on Reynolds (Box 512)
        - Hemings, Sally, 4 folders (Box 512)
        - Israel, Israel (Box 513)
        - Jefferson (Box 513)
        - Jefferson and Callender (Box 513)
        - Jefferson by Joseph Ellis (Box 513)
        - Jefferson - library (Box 513)
        - Jefferson pays Callender (Box 513)
        - Jefferson: The Scene of Europe (Box 513)
        - "A Journeyman, Either in Law or Politics," John Beckley (Box 513)
        - Light horse Harry Lee (Oversize 29)
        - Malone chapters on Jefferson (Box 513)
        - Maria Reynolds (Box 513)
        - National Archives materials (Box 520)
        - The Prospect Before Us (Oversize 29)
        - Quid (Box 513)
        - The Recorder (Oversize 30)
        - Richmond records (Box 513)
        - Ronda (Box 513)
        - Sedgwick and Co, James T. Callender (Box 513)
        - Sedition (Box 513)
        - Ships (Box 513)
        - Sketches of the History of America, James T. Callender, 2 folders (Box 513)
        - The Story of the Bill of Rights: Documents, Rare Imprints, and Portraits to Commemorate (Box 520)
        - Trial of James T. Callender (Box 513)
        - Various articles regarding Hamiliton and Callender (Oversize 30)
        - Walker (Box 514)
        - Walker affair (Box 514)
        - Walker - Jefferson (Box 514)
        - Washington (Box 514)
        - Washington's inaugural address of 1789, reproduction (Oversize 30)
        - Washington's official map of Yorktown, reproduction (Oversize 30)
      - Research requests (Box 514)
      - Reviews, 4 folders (Box 514)
      - Royalties (Box 514)
      - Thank-you letters, 2 folders (Box 514)
    - Sleeper Spy
      - Book jacket cover (Box 453)
      - Contract (Box 453)
      - Correspondence
        - Janklow (Box 453)
        - Random House (Box 453)
      - Draft edits, prologue and chapters; 7 folders (Box 453)
      - Draft edits, chapters; 2 folders (Box 454)
      - Draft edits, chapters and epilogue; 2 folders (Box 514)
      - Editor's letters with edits (Box 514)
      - Freebie list (Box 515)
      - Manuscript, pages 1-615; 12 folders (Box 515)
      - Printed materials (Box 515)
      - Publicity (Box 515)
      - Research notes (Box 515)
      - Research notes, Aldrich Ames (Box 516)
      - Reviews, 4 folders (Box 516)
      - Thank-you letters, 2 folders (Box 516)
    - Spread the Word
      - Correspondence, Janklow and Nesbit Associates (Box 454)
      - Research notes
        - Ah, Ur (Box 454)
        - Alpha Male (Box 454)
        - Aphetic Verbal Doppelganger (Box 454)
        - Babes Up in Arms (Box 454)
        - Betwixt "Among" and "Between" (Box 454)
        - The Bloopie Awards I, II, III (Box 454)
        - A Bridge Too Far (Box 454)
        - A Bridge Too Fur (Box 454)
        - Bungee Jumping (Box 454)
        - Centered on "Focused" (Box 454)
        - Chat Me Up (Box 454)
        - Compellence or Compellance? (Box 454)
        - Cut Them Some Slack (Box 454)
        - Defuse Those Participles (Box 454)
        - Diddle-Daddle (Box 454)
        - Dog's Breakfast (Box 454)
        - Don't Worry, Be Peppy (Box 454)
        - Downsize That Special Sea Change (Box 454)
        - Dr. Livingstone, I Presume? Assume? Suppose? (Box 454)
        - Driven-Driven (Box 454)
        - Ethnic Cleansing (Box 454)
        - Etymological Discovery (Box 454)
        - Fashionable Words (Box 454)
        - Fly Me to the Zone (Box 454)
        - Foam Fell on Alabama (Box 454)
        - Footprints on the Infobahn (Box 454)
        - Frankly Speaking (Box 454)
        - Freaked on Clout (Box 454)
        - Free Lunch (Box 454)
        - The Fuzz and the Wuzz (Box 454)
        - Get a Life! (Box 454)
        - Get Off My Laptop (Box 454)
        - Good-Deed Dungeon (Box 454)
        - The Gotcha! Gang (Box 455)
        - Grand Allusions (Box 455)
        - A Heads Up on Fulsome (Box 455)
        - Health Care Provider, Heal Thyself (Box 455)
        - The "Horny" Dilemma (Box 455)
        - The Hunt for "Near Abroad" (Box 455)
        - Impassioned Executive (Box 455)
        - The Imperious Imperative (Box 455)
        - In Contradistinction to Jejune (Box 455)
        - In the Deep Heart's Core (Box 455)
        - In the Mist, In the Dust (Box 455)
        - Inaugural Nitpicks (Box 455)
        - Incorrections (Box 455)
        - Jericho, Trumpets, Walls, Etc. (Box 455)
        - Keep Your Eye upon the Bagel (Box 455)
        - Kubla's Comeback (Box 455)
        - The Latest Issue (Box 455)
        - Leaping the Rhetorical Gap (Box 455)
        - Left Is Not Right (Box 455)
        - Let 'Er Rip (Box 455)
        - Linguaclip (Box 455)
        - Long Word's Return (Box 455)
        - Maid Service (Box 455)
        - Mangled Metaphors (Box 455)
        - Marley's Ghost Rides the Trolley (Box 455)
        - Masterful Meltdown (Box 455)
        - Meanwhile, Back at the Revanche (Box 455)
        - Mind Games (Box 455)
        - Morphin' Time (Box 455)
        - Motherese (Box 455)
        - Mouthing On (Box 455)
        - Movin' On (Box 455)
        - My Old Flame (Box 455)
        - Newtonian Linguistics (Box 455)
        - [Obit] E. J. Kahn Jr. (Box 455)
        - Off Of (Box 456)
        - Off Those Ramparts (Box 456)
        - On the Edge (Box 456)
        - Only the Factoids (Box 456)
        - Out of Control (Box 456)
        - Ozarks on the Potomac (Box 456)
        - Packagers (Box 456)
        - Paw (Box 456)
        - Pinchbeck (Box 456)
        - Pinpricks (Box 456)
        - Post Card (Box 456)
        - Presenting: OLBWS (Box 456)
        - A Prevent Defense (Box 456)
        - The Process Process (Box 456)
        - Pun Jab (Box 456)
        - Ragtag Modalities (Box 456)
        - REGO Is a MEGO (Box 456)
        - Return of the Mondegreens (Box 456)
        - Satan's Hometown (Box 456)
        - Save Our Zoo from Language Predators (Box 456)
        - Scalia v. Merriam-Webster (Box 456)
        - Shebang (Box 456)
        - Shmush (Box 456)
        - Shoulda-Coulda-Woulda (Box 456)
        - Sic 'Em (Box 456)
        - Simpsonese (Box 456)
        - Skinny Marink (Box 456)
        - Slur Patrol I (Box 456)
        - Slur Patrol II (Box 456)
        - Smearing It On, Rubbing It In (Box 456)
        - Smilin' Thru? (Box 456)
        - Spectacular Hair Day (Box 456)
        - Squad, Squad Report (Box 456)
        - Stand and Deliver (Box 456)
        - State of the Now (Box 456)
        - Status Report (Box 456)
        - Stiffed Again (Box 456)
        - Stormy Whether - or Not? (Box 456)
        - Stud Muffin's Buzz-Kill (Box 457)
        - Style War: English vs. Murkin (Box 457)
        - Sucking Up (Box 457)
        - Surrender, Already (Box 457)
        - There Are Those Who Say (Box 457)
        - Tough Sell (Box 457)
        - Trigger-Happy (Box 457)
        - Trophy Wife (Box 457)
        - Vengeance Is Mine (Box 457)
        - Vetter Vets Vet (Box 457)
        - Views on Sensibilities (Box 457)
        - Way Out, Ways In, Right Away (Box 457)
        - Welcome to "-icity" City (Box 457)
        - What Hath God Unwrought? (Box 457)
        - Who's Got "Security"? (Box 457)
        - What's So Funny About Bananas? (Box 457)
        - What's With "With"? (Box 457)
        - Whence "White"? (Box 457)
        - Whitewater Words (Box 457)
        - Whitewaterese (Box 457)
        - Whole Nine Yards (Box 457)
        - Woe unto Life (Box 457)
        - The Word from the Pope (Box 457)
        - Words Out in the Cold (Box 457)
        - Year's Best Lede (Box 457)
        - Zero Misteaks (Box 457)
      - Thank-you letters (Box 457)
      - Manuscript
        - Setting copy (Box 457)
        - Setting copy, 4 folders (Box 458)
      - Production records
        - Page proofs
          - 1st pass, 2 folders (Box 458)
          - [2nd pass] Pages 1-306, 4 folders (Box 459)
      - Internal memos, miscellaneous (Box 459)
      - Cuts (Box 459)
      - Reader permissions
        - A-M, 3 folders (Box 459)
        - N-Z, miscellaneous, 3 folders (Box 460)
    - Take My Word for It (More on Language from William Safire)
      - Correspondence
        - [General] (Box 460)
        - Janklow Associates (Box 460)
        - Times Books (Box 460)
      - Catalog (Box 460)
      - Freebie list (Box 460)
      - Index (Box 460)
      - Reviews (Box 460)
      - Thank-you letters (Box 460)
      - Working copy, 2 folders (Box 460)
    - Watching My Language: Adventures in the Word Trade
      - Correspondence
        - [General] (Box 460)
        - Janklow and Nesbit Associates (Box 460)
        - Random House (Box 460)
      - Freebie lists (Box 460)
      - Research notes
        - Introduction, Prettification Patrol (Box 460)
        - The Arch Triumphalist (Box 461)
        - An Article Article (Box 461)
        - Banausic Ain't Banal (Box 461)
        - Belittling the Diminutive (Box 461)
        - The "Bizarre" Bazaar (Box 461)
        - The Bloopie Awards (Box 461)
        - Blowout! (Box 461)
        - Born To Set It Right (Box 461)
        - Britishisms Lying Doggo (Box 461)
        - Bubble, Bubble, Toil and Transition (Box 461)
        - Buffalo Bill Not Defunct (Box 461)
        - But Who Won on Language? (Box 461)
        - Campaign Trailese (Box 461)
        - Confederacy Rises Again (Box 461)
        - Cordialities and Crushes (Box 461)
        - Crack That Code (Box 461)
        - Dig Those Digerati (Box 461)
        - Disagreeing to Agree (Box 461)
        - The Disappointed -ed (Box 461)
        - Double Dip or Dead-Cat Bounce? (Box 461)
        - Electability (Box 461)
        - El Ni~no (Box 461)
        - Engagement Party (Box 461)
        - Enjoy! (Box 461)
        - The Evolving Moment (Box 461)
        - Explicit Is Not a Dirty Word (Box 461)
        - Family Values (Box 461)
        - The Game's the Thing (Box 461)
        - Get It? (Box 462)
        - Get With the Program (Box 462)
        - Gifts of Gab (Box 462)
        - Greenhorn (Box 462)
        - Growing Down Grows Up (Box 462)
        - Hard Line (Box 462)
        - #@/\!= Hash, At, Slash, Backslash, Open, Close, Bang (Box 462)
        - Heads Up! (Box 462)
        - Hyphenated Americans (Box 462)
        - Hypothalamus High (Box 462)
        - Impregnating the Pause (Box 462)
        - Inside the Circumferential Highway (Box 462)
        - In Your Face (Box 462)
        - It's a Rain Forest Out There (Box 462)
        - Jump-Start Those Animal Spirits (Box 462)
        - Kinder Than Who? (Box 462)
        - Let Forthcoming Come Forth (Box 462)
        - Let's Kill All the Copy Editors (Box 462)
        - Linguistically Correct (Box 462)
        - Listing to Portmanteau (Box 462)
        - Lying Low (Box 462)
        - Mailbag (Box 462)
        - Manhandling the Handlers (Box 462)
        - McQueen's English (Box 462)
        - Me: "Don't Finish My - ." You: "Sentence." Meta-phor (Box 462)
        - The Mocking "Do" (Box 462)
        - Modifier's Lib (Box 462)
        - Multi Multi- (Box 462)
        - Name That Disease (Box 462)
        - The New Omics (Box 463)
        - Nifty Gifties (Box 463)
        - Night Arrant (Box 463)
        - Noblesse Largess (Box 463)
        - No Picnic (Box 463)
        - Not! (Box 463)
        - Not Me (Box 463)
        - Ode on a G-String (Box 463)
        - On Being Layered (Box 463)
        - O Ye Gates (Box 463)
        - Peace-ese (Box 463)
        - Perotspeak (Box 463)
        - Phrasedick Alert: Etymons Wanted (Box 463)
        - Poetic Allusion Watch (Box 463)
        - Policy Wonkmanship (Box 463)
        - The Prep-Droppers (Box 463)
        - Quick, Henry, the Fix (Box 463)
        - The Rage Rage (Box 463)
        - The Rap on Hip-Hop (Box 463)
        - Reach, Crescendo (Box 463)
        - The Retronymbles (Box 463)
        - Seize the Hour, Day or Moment (Box 463)
        - The Seven-Year Itch (Box 463)
        - Sighted Supersession, Sank Same (Box 463)
        - Stulte Agitur Oeconomia (Box 463)
        - The Take on Voice (Box 463)
        - Target: Declinism (Box 463)
        - Teeth on the Sidewalk (Box 463)
        - Tense Encounter (Box 463)
        - There's No Wearware (Box 463)
        - The Third Way (Box 463)
        - -30- (Box 463)
        - This Ol' House (Box 463)
        - To Remind (Box 463)
        - Tossing Our Cookies (Box 463)
        - An Unstaid Heads-up (Box 463)
        - Virtual Reality (Box 463)
        - Voice Over (Box 463)
        - Warlords, Bandits, Thugs and Regional Leaders (Box 463)
        - Wedges and Bounces (Box 463)
        - Whacking the Suits (Box 464)
        - Whack, You're Dead (Box 464)
        - What to Call the Russians (Box 464)
        - What to Do with "Soviet"? (Box 464)
        - When Putsch Comes To Coup (Box 464)
        - Wholly of Whollies (Box 464)
        - Who Trusts Whom? (Box 464)
        - The Winged Frog (Box 464)
        - Wise Guys Finish Last (Box 464)
        - Word Needed (Box 464)
      - Thank-you letters (Box 464)
      - Manuscript, 7 folders (Box 464)
      - Manuscript, 3 folders (Box 465)
      - Internal memos, miscellany (Box 465)
    - What's the Good Word?
      - Working copy, 2 folders (Box 465)
    - You Could Look It Up
      - Correspondence, Times Books (Box 465)
      - Book jacket covers (Box 465)
      - Catalogs (Box 465)
      - Foreward (Box 465)
      - Freebie lists (Box 465)
      - Research notes
        - Forewords March (Box 465)
        - Aboard the Zoo Plane (Box 465)
        - Abort the Correction! Apostrophe Catastrophe (Box 465)
        - Attaboy, Adamant (Box 465)
        - Away With You, Nosy Parker (Box 465)
        - Banned Words (Box 465)
        - Bark Off (Box 465)
        - The Beltway Bandits (Box 465)
        - Beware the Basher (Box 465)
        - Beware the Virtuallies (Box 465)
        - Blow 'Em Away (Box 465)
        - Booming the Babies (Box 465)
        - The Build-Down Buildup (Box 465)
        - Cantonlike Cardinal Is My Middle Name (Box 465)
        - Claim to Fame Clause Wits (Box 465)
        - Cloud Seven Plus Two (Box 465)
        - Comes the Evolution (Box 465)
        - Commander in Thief (Box 465)
        - Condone (Box 465)
        - Cover Me (Box 466)
        - A Czar Is Not a Tsar (Box 466)
        - Dash It All (Box 466)
        - Dash of Grenadine (Box 466)
        - Dearest Computer (Box 466)
        - Debating Words (Box 466)
        - Dental Deceit (Box 466)
        - Detritus (Box 466)
        - Doing Pragma (Box 466)
        - Downsurging Uptick (Box 466)
        - Dust Heaps of History (Box 466)
        - Euph Will Be Served (Box 466)
        - Eurolingo (Box 466)
        - Forgive Me, But (Box 466)
        - Front-Loading (Box 466)
        - Gin Up (Box 466)
        - Hallow Rings Hollow (Box 466)
        - Her Majesty Is Not Enthused (Box 466)
        - Hide That Agenda (Box 466)
        - Hotdogging It (Box 466)
        - Huggermugger (Box 466)
        - Inhumanism (Box 466)
        - Internecine Incivility (Box 466)
        - Ize Right? (Box 466)
        - Juggernaughty but Nice (Box 466)
        - Knowing Your Fiddlesticks, 2 folders (Box 466)
        - Like, No (Box 466)
        - Logue-Rolling (Box 466)
        - Loud Abjection (Box 466)
        - Men! (Box 466)
        - Mindset in Concrete (Box 466)
        - Mousse Call (Box 466)
        - My Dear Computer (Box 466)
        - My Name Ain't Mac, Buddy, 2 folders (Box 466)
        - My Nomen Is Klatura (Box 467)
        - Never Call Retreat (Box 467)
        - Noble Savage (Box 467)
        - Not Knowing from Beans (Box 467)
        - Nowhearthis, Inc. (Box 467)
        - Oh, the Pain (Box 467)
        - Pale Lilac Speaks, 3 folders (Box 467)
        - Paths of Glory (Box 467)
        - Play Down the Alibi (Box 467)
        - Pogey-Bait (Box 467)
        - Probab-lee (Box 467)
        - Pro-Macassar (Box 467)
        - Punch-Line English, 2 folders (Box 467)
        - Respectfully Disagree (Box 467)
        - R. S. V. I. P. (Box 467)
        - Saying a Mouthful (Box 467)
        - Scoreless on the Year (Box 467)
        - Secret Plan (Box 467)
        - Shambling Along (Box 467)
        - Shambolic (Box 467)
        - Sharp Elbows (Box 467)
        - Shoo-In (Box 467)
        - Short Quick In (Box 467)
        - The Skinny on Skinny (Box 467)
        - The Sleaze Factor (Box 467)
        - Spell Your Dreams Away (Box 467)
        - The Spirit Is Mean (Box 467)
        - Squad Squad Hat Trick (Box 467)
        - Squad Squad Strikes Yet Again (Box 467)
        - Stine or Steen? (Box 468)
        - Straightening "Straits" (Box 468)
        - Street-Smart (Box 468)
        - Sure Thing (Box 468)
        - Sweet Talk (Box 468)
        - Taint So (Box 468)
        - Tapetalk (Box 468)
        - The Teeny-Weeny Master Spy (Box 468)
        - That Says It All (Box 468)
        - Thinking Big (Box 468)
        - Times Marches On Today's Especial (Box 468)
        - To the Manner Hoisted (Box 468)
        - Up the Downtime (Box 468)
        - Walls Have Ears (Box 468)
        - Welcome to Splitsville (Box 468)
        - When You Say That, Resile (Box 468)
        - Who's a Patsy? (Box 468)
        - The Wicked Which and the Comma (Box 468)
        - Wired! (Box 468)
        - With Coolness Toward None (Box 468)
        - The Woid on -Oid (Box 468)
        - Would That Mine Adversary (Box 468)
        - Yawners and Sleepers (Box 468)
        - Yip, Yap, Yumpies Zapmanship (Box 468)
        - Miscellaneous (Box 468)
      - Reviews (Box 468)
      - Sales flyers (Box 468)
      - Thank-you letters (Box 468)
      - Working copy (Box 468)
      - Working copy (Box 469)
  - Book ideas
    - Redefinitions, 10 folders (Box 469)
    - Safire's Usage Book, 2 folders (Box 470)
  - Book jackets
    - Book jackets from Safire's published books, See also Writings by others, Book jackets; book jackets were removed from the books in Safire's personal library. Safire's library of books have been catalogued and are now located in the Safire Room on the sixth floor of Bird Library. (Oversize 35)
  - Books with Leonard Safir
    - Great Answers to Great Questions, 3 folders (Box 470)
    - Leadership
      - Correspondence (Box 470)
      - Freebie lists (Box 470)
      - Reviews (Box 470)
    - More Good Advice
      - Contract (Box 470)
      - Correspondence (Box 470)
      - Preface (Box 470)
    - Words of Wisdom
      - Freebie lists (Box 470)
      - Prolegomenon (Box 470)
      - Reviews (Box 470)
      - Royalties (Box 470)
      - Thank-you letters (Box 470)
  - Indices
    - Citation cards (Oversize 14)
    - Citation cards (Oversize 15)
    - Citation cards (Oversize 16)
    - Citation cards (Oversize 17)
  - Miscellaneous book correspondence
    - [General], 6 folders (Box 471)
    - Contracts, 3 folders (Box 471)
    - Electronic rights (Box 471)
    - Electronic rights, 3 folders (Box 472)
    - Miscellaneous book inserts, 10 folders (Box 472)
    - Miscellaneous book inserts - News clippings, 4 folders (Box 472)
  - Other Writings
    - Articles
      - "Advice to Prospective College Men," unpublished, undated (Box 473)
      - "Bush's Cabinet," The New York Times Magazine, 25 Mar 1990 (Oversize 18)
      - "Bush's Gamble," The New York Times Magazine, 18 Oct 1992 (Oversize 18)
      - "Curtain Call: A Report on an Army Night Patrol Along the Iron Curtain," unpublished, undated (Box 473)
      - "The Day Madison Avenue Played Sokolniki Park," The Overseas Press Bulletin, 12 Sep 1959 (Box 473)
      - "Dear John: How Not to Write to a GI," unpublished, undated (Box 473)
      - "Dr. Rockwell's Patients Always Die: A True Story of an American Inventor," unpublished, undated (Box 473)
      - "The Great American Love Affair with Cars," Reader's Digest, May 1976 (Box 473)
      - "How PR Man uses Paid Advertising," Editor and Publisher, 18 Apr 1959 (Box 473)
      - "The International Pastime: A Baseball Legend," unpublished, undated; with Leonard Safire (Box 473)
      - "Last Days in the Bunker," The New York Times Magazine, 18 Aug 1974 (Oversize 18)
      - "Lincoln Meets the Press, The New York Times Magazine, Aug 1987 (Oversize 18)
      - "My First One Thousand Messes: A GI View of Army Chow," unpublished (Box 473)
      - "The Poor Mans Hall of Fame," unpublished, undated (Box 473)
      - "The Race for Clout," The New York Times Magazine, 20 Jun 1993 (Oversize 18)
      - "Reagan's Next Term: His Agenda, His Prospects," The New York Times Magazine, 13 Jan 1985 (Oversize 18)
      - "The Real 'Long John Silver,'" unpublished, undated (Box 473)
      - "Ringing Rhetoric," The New York Times Magazine, 19 Aug 1984 (Oversize 18)
      - "Ten Myths About the Reagan Debacle," The New York Times Magazine, 22 Mar 1987 (Oversize 18)
      - "Tenderizing the Trap: How to Furnish a Seductive Apartment," unpublished, undated (Box 473)
      - "The Three Dimensional Heart," unpublished, undated (Box 473)
      - "Tug-O-War," The New York Times Magazine, 13 Sep 1987 (Oversize 18)
      - Untitled article regarding Peter Olaf Sasha, unpublished, undated (Box 473)
      - Untitled article regarding two soldiers on the West-East border, unpublished, undated (Box 473)
      - Untitled, Paris Match, 1975 (Box 473)
      - "A War on Fuzziness," Today's Education, Nov-Dec 1976 (Box 473)
      - "Was Mr. Vanderbilt Right?" PR: The Quarterly Review of Public Relations, Jan 1960 (Box 473)
      - "Where Have All the Republicans Gone?" Harper's, 1976 (Box 473)
    - "Close-Up"
      - Book proposal (Box 516)
      - Research files, A-C, 5 folders (Box 516)
      - Research files, D-L, 10 folders (Box 517)
      - Research files, M-V, 11 folders (Box 518)
      - Research files, W and Y (Box 519)
    - Essays
      - "The All-Purpose Political Speech," The Rhetoric of Our Times (Box 473)
      - CEO Report: A Supplement to Chief Executive Magazine, Andersen Consulting (Box 473)
      - College non-fiction, essays that Safire wrote during his time at college at Syracuse University (Box 473)
      - The New York Times News Service, Editor's Guide (1997-1998) (Box 473)
      - "Ten Commandments of columny," The Bulletin of the American Society of Newspaper Editors, November 1981 (Box 473)
      - Times Talk: News About the People of The New York Times, December 1987 (Box 473)
    - Reviews
      - "The Dictionary of Biographical Quotation," The New York Times Book Review, December 24, 1978 (Box 473)
      - "Goodbye To Privacy," The New York Times Book Review, April 10, 2005 (Oversize 18)
      - "Lincoln Monuments," The New York Times Book Review, February 8, 2009 (Box 473)
      - "Lincoln Monuments," The New York Times Book Review, February 8, 2009 (Box 473)
      - "An Old Fox Knows Many Things," The New York Times Book Review, September 6, 1987 (Box 473)
      - "The One-Man Fourth Estate," The New York Times Book Review, June 6, 1982 (Box 473)
      - "The One-Man Fourth Estate," The New York Times Book Review, June 6, 1982; 2 additional copies (Oversize 18)
      - "A Washington Monument," The New York Times Book Review, October 1, 1995 (Oversize 18)